[{"question":"<p><strong>There are 8 green ball, 4 blue balls and 3 white balls in a box. Then 1 greenand 1 blue balls are taken from the box and put away. What is&nbsp; the probability that a blue ball is selected at random from the box?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3\/13","2\/13","4\/15","3\/15"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A student measures a piece of rope and found it was 127m long. If the actual length of the rope was 125m, what was the percentage error in the measurement?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1.6%","1.0%","0.8%","0.16%"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>At what rate will the interest on N500 increase to N25 in 5 years reckoning&nbsp; in simple interest ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2 %","1%","4%","5%"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>If y varies directly as the square root of x and y = 3 when x = 16, calculate y when x = 64<\/strong><\/p>","options":["12","3","5","6"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The 3rd term of an arithmetic progression is 8 and the 7th term is -28. Find the 10th term of the progression.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-43","-164","164","44"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>If x *y= x-y<sup>2<\/sup>, find the value of (2*3)*5<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-25","25","-32","32"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Five years ago, a father was 3 times as old as his son. Now, their combined ages amount to 110 years. Thus, the present age of the father is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["75 years","60 years","98 years","80 years"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Mother reduced the quantity of food bought for the family by 10% when she found that the cost of living had increased by 15%. Thus the fractional increase in the family food bill is now<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1\/12","6\/35","19\/300","7\/200"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a soccer competition in one season, a club had scored the following goals: 2,0,3,3,2,1,4,0,0,5,1,0,2,2,1,3,1,4,1, and 1. The mean, median and mode are respectively.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1,1.8,and1.5","1.8,1.5 and 1","1.8,1 and 1.5","1.5, 1 and 1.8"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Two triangles have the same area if <\/strong><\/p>","options":["Two sides in one triangle are equal to two sides in the other.","Three sides in one triangle are equal to three sides in the other.","Two angles in one triangle are equal to two angles in the other.","Three angles in one triangle are equal to three angles in the other."],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>If 25x-1 = 64 (5\/2)<sup>6<\/sup>, then x has the value<\/strong><\/p>","options":["7","4","32","5"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The smallest number such that when it is divided by 8 has a remainder of 6 and when it is divided by 9 has a remainder of 7 is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["50","70","80","60"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>When a dealer sells a bicycle for N81 he makes profitof 8%. What did he pay for the bicycle ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N74","N74.52","N75","N75.52"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A man and his wife went to buy article costing N400. The woman had 10% of the cost and the man 40% of the remainder. How much did they have altogether.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N216","N200","N184","N144"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a school there are 35 students in class 2A and 40 in 2B. The mean score for class 2A in a Mathematics examination is 60.00 and that for 2B in the paper is 52.5. Find, to one place of decimals, the mean of the combined classes.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["56.5","56.0","56.3","56.2"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A set of data contains a total of 130 items which are divided into six groups for display on a pie chart. If one of the groups contains 26 items then the sector representing this group on the pie chart contains an angle x at the centre of the circle where x is <\/strong><\/p>","options":["3","60","70","72"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A pentagon has four of its angles equal. If the size of the fifth angle is 60\u00b0 find the size of each of the four equal angles.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["60\u00b0","108\u00b0","120\u00b0","150\u00b0"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What will be the value of k so that the equation Kx<sup>2<\/sup> - 4x+1=0 has equal roots ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2","3","4","8"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>If x varies inversely as y, and y varies directly as the square root of z, and z varies directly as 1\/w<sup>2<\/sup>, write down in words how x varies with w.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["x varies inversely as w<sup>-1<\/sup>","x varies directly as w<sup>-1<\/sup>","x varies directly as w","x varies inversely as w"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A bag contain 3 apples, r oranges and 3 bananas. What is the probability&nbsp; of selecting a banana and then an apple ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["9\/100","9\/10","1\/10","2\/3"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In how many ways can a committe of 3 women and 4 men be chosen from 6 men and 5 women<\/strong><\/p>","options":["250","25","50","100"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Write down the number 0.0052048 correct to three significant figures.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0.005","0.0052","0.00521","0.00520"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Write the decimal number 39 to base 2.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["110111","100111","111000","110111"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the smallest number by which 252 can be multiplied to obtain a perfect square.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2","3","7","5"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>An open rectangular box externally measures 4m x 3m x 4m. Find the costs of painting the box eternally if it cost N2.00 to paint one square metre<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N116.0","N113.00","N112.00","N136.00"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>If Musa scored 75 in Biology instead of 57, his average mark in four subjects would have been 60. What was his total mark ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["200","222","322","122"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Sola deposited #150.00 in the bank. At the end of 5 years, the simple interest on the princinpal was #55.00. At what rate per annum was the interest paid ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6.3 3%","8.3 3%","7.32%","7.33%"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the sum of the 20 terms in an arithmetic progression whose first term is&nbsp; 7 and the last term is 117.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["239","1240","1340","1440"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A trader realizes 10x-X<sup>2<\/sup>naira profit from the salae of x bags of corn. How many bags will give him the maximum profit ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6","4","3","5"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>X and Y are two events. The probability of X or Y is&nbsp; 0.7 and the probability of X is 0.4. If X and Y are independent, find the probability of Y.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0.2","0.4","0.5","0.3"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>An equilateral triangle of side 3cm is inscribed a circle. Find the radius of the circle.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1.73cm","2.12cm","3.01cm","0.73cm"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a class of 40 students 32 offer Mathematics,24 offer physics and 4 offer neither Mathematics nor Physics. How many offer both Mathematics and Physics ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["16","21","19","20"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A cinema hall contains a certain number&nbsp; of people. If 22.5% are children 47.5% are men and 84 are women, find the number of men in the hall.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["133","132","130","123"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>An arc of a circle subtends an angle of 30 on the circumference of a circle of radius 21cm. Find the length of the arc.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["11cm","22cm","66cm","44cm"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The mean of a set of six numbers is 60. If the mean of the first five is 50, find the sixth number in the set.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["100","120","105","110"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The sum of the interior angles of a regular polygon is 1800\u00b0. Calculate the size of one exterior angle of the polygon.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["45<sup>-1<\/sup>","60<sup>-1<\/sup>","30<sup>-1<\/sup>","90<sup>-1<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the simple interest rate percent per annum at which #1,000 accumulates to #1,240 in 3 years.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["8%","7%","6%","5%"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A man invested #5000 for 9 months at 4%. What is the simple interest ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N220","N130","N150","N250"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>If log<sub>3<\/sub>18+log<sub>3<\/sub>3-log<sub>3<\/sub>x&nbsp;= 3, find x.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2","1","0","3"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Raila has 7 different posters to be hanged in her bedroom, living room, and kitchen. Assuming she has plans to replace at least a poster in each of the 3 rooms, how many choices does she have?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["49","170","210","21"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the sum of the first 18 terms of the series 3, 6, 9, . . . , 36<\/strong><\/p>","options":["513","505","433","635"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The second term of a geometric series is 4 while the fourth term is 16. Find the sum of the first five terms.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["60","54","64","62"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the size of each interior angle of a 12-sided regular polygon ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["120<sup>-1<\/sup>","150<sup>-1<\/sup>","30<sup>-1<\/sup>","180<sup>-1<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A solid metal cube of side 3cm is placed in a rectangular tank of dimensions 3, 4 and&nbsp; 5cm. What volume of water can the tank now&nbsp; hold<\/strong><\/p>","options":["48cm<sup>3<\/sup>","33cm<sup>3<\/sup>","60cm<sup>3<\/sup>","27cm<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The perpendicular bisector of a line XY is the locus of a point<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Whose distance from X is always twice its distance from Y","Whose distance from Y is always twice its distance from X","Which moves on the line XY","Which is equidistance from the points X and Y"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The midpoint of P (x, y) and Q (8, 6) is (5, 8). Find x and y.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(2, 10)","(2, 8)","(2, 12)","(2, 6)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A man walks 100m due West from a point X to Y,he then walks 100m due North to a point Z. Find the bearing of X from Z.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["195<sup>-1<\/sup>","135<sup>-1<\/sup>","225<sup>-1<\/sup>","045<sup>-1<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The derivative of (2x+1)(3x+1) is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["12x+1","6x+5","6x+1","12x+5"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The sum of four consecutive integers is 34. Find the least of these numbers.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6","8","7","5"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A man earns N3500 per month out of which he spends 15%&nbsp; on his children's education. If he spends additional N1950 on food, how much does he have left?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N525","N1025","N1950","N2975"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a class of 46 students, 22 play football and 26 play volleyball. If 3 students play both games, how many play neither ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1","2","3","4"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The nth term of a sequence is n<sup>2<\/sup> - 6n-4. Find the sum of the 3rd and 4th terms.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["24","23","-24","-25"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The binary operation is defined on the set of integers such that&nbsp;<em>p*q&nbsp;= pq+p-q.&nbsp;<\/em>Find 2*(3*4).<\/strong><\/p>","options":["11","13","15","22"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Calculate the volume of a cuboid of length 0.76cm,&nbsp; breadth 2.6 cm and height 0.82cm.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3.92cm<sup>3<\/sup>","2.13cm<sup>3<\/sup>","1.97cm<sup>3<\/sup>","1.62cm<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A man stands on a tree 150cm high and see a boat an angle of depression of 74<sup>0<\/sup>. Find the distance of the boat from the base of the tree.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["52cm","43cm","40cm","15cm"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The mean of seven numbers is 96. If the eight number is added, athe mean becomes 112. Find the eight number.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["126","180","216","224"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the median of 2,3,7,3,4,5,8,9,9,4,5,3,4,2 and 5<\/strong><\/p>","options":["9","8","7","4"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the standard deviation of 2,3,8, 10 and 12.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3.9","4.9","5.9","6.9"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In how many ways can the letters of the word TOTALITY be arranged ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6720","6270","6207","6027"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"}]